Guide to the James and Margaret Goff Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Addendum -2010, Series VIII
  - Nicaragua
    - Miscellaneous, 1984, 1991-1992 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, newspaper clippings, 1980, 1983, 1987, 1989, 1992, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Missionaries, correspondence, 1985, 1988-1989, 1992 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - The New York Times, newspaper clippings, 1989 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Nicaragua Network, 1993, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Nicarauga Network fundraising letters, 1989-1990 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Nicaragua News Service, June 1991-February 1993 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Nicaragua News Service, February 1993-July 1995 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Nicaraguan issues re. socio/political concerns, correspondence, 1983, 1986, 1992, 1993 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Non-profit fundraising letters, 1983, 1988-1997, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Nicaragua-United States Friendship Office, correspondence and information packets, 1992-1995 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Papers re. accusation of religous persecution in Nicaragua, 1984 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Presbyterian Church (U.S.A.) and Nicaragua (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Religion, newspaper clippings, 1987, 1989, 1993 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Religious pamphlets re. advent, revolution in Nicaragua, and the Miskitos, 1993, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Sandinista government, newspaper clippings, 1987-1993 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Sandinista government publications re. civil defense, education, Nicaragua vs C.I.A, and prison reform, 1980, 1983, 1986 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - The Sandinistas and the Miskitos by C. Alton Robertson, dissertation, 1990 January (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - U.S. citizens' observations, articles, sermons, 1986-1991, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - U.S. foreign relations with Nicaragua, newspaper clippings, 1983, 1986, 1992-1993 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Women and the revolution, information packet (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Panama
    - United States vs. Noriega, newspaper clippings, December 18-27, 1989 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Puerto Rico
    - Booklets incl. Puerto Rico: A People Challenging Colonialism, La Presencia Militar de Estados Unidos en Puerto Rico, 1976, 1985, 1990 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Central America
    - Alert! Focus on Central America newspaper, November 1989-October 1990 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Alert! Focus on Central America newspaper, Dec/Jan 1991-Feb/March 1992 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Basta! National Journal of the Chicago Religious Task Force on Central America, December 1987, June 1998 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Central American Information Bulletin newsletter, January 1987-December 1988 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - LASA Forum (Latin American Studies Association) newsletter, Winter 1989-Summer 1990 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - LASA Forum newsletter, Fall 1990-Fall 1992 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - LASA Forum newsletter, Winter 1993-Winter 1995 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - LASA Forum newsletter, Winter 1997-Winter 1998 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous newsletters, 1991-1998 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Regionews from Managua newsletter, July-December 1989 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Revista Justica y Paz periodical, May-June 1992, January 1994 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Times of the Americas newspaper, December 1991-January 1992 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Times of the Americas newspaper, February-March 1992 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Booklets incl. Central America 1980, Invasion: a Guide to the U.S. Military Presence in Central America, Low Intensity Conflict: the New Battlefield in Central America, 1980-1986 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Booklets incl. Central America Without Crying Uncle, The United States in Search of Enemies: a Selected "National Security" Reading List, 1987-1988 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Booklets incl. Sow in Tears, Reap in Joy, A Fresh Start: New Paths for U.S. Economic Policy Toward Central America, 1990-1993 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - CIDOC Cuadernos Catalog de Publicaciones, 1971, 1972 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Immigration Issues, brochures, newspaper clippings, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - The Kissinger Report, January 10, 1984 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Latin American Studies Association, 1986-1988, 1992 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Latin American Studies Association, 1994, 1997-1998 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Map 'N' Facts: Central America, 1990 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 1990-1991 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous non-profit fundraising letters, 1991-1997, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Report on Issues Related to Resolution for Council Action Declaring Seattle a Sanctuary for Salvadoran and Guatemalan Refugees, August 30, 1985 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Central America: Religion and Human Rights
    - Challenge: Faith and Action in Central America newsletter, 1990-1995 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Jubileo año 2000 newsletter, 1997-1999 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous newsletters, 1977-2001 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - The Pomona Valley Council for Peace and Peace with Justice Coalition Center Newsletter, 1989-1994 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - The Pomona Valley Council for Peace and Peace with Justice Coalition Center Newsletter, 1995-2000 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - RESIST: a Call to Resist Illegitimate Authority newsletter, 1994-1995 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Witness for Peace Newsletter; Witness for Peace: Southwest Newsletter; Witness for Peace: Southern California Newsletter, 1989-1993 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Booklets incl. Basic Ecclesiastical Statistics for Latin America 1958, Roman Catholicism and Religious Liberty, Aventura y Esperanza: los Cristianos y la Crisis en Centroamérica, 1958-1959, 1983-1984 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Booklets incl. Presbyterians and Peacemaking: Are We Now Called to Resistance? (Supplemental Readings), Peacemaking II: U.S. Religious Statements on Central America, Peacemaking III, Behind the Mask: Human Rights in Asia and Latin America, 1984-1988 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Booklets incl. Madre Tierra, Women and Human Rights: The Struggle for Equality, 1988, 1993-1995 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Central America and the Religious Right, incl. The New Right Humanitarians and The Pat Robertson File, 1987 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - The Church and Environmental Issues, 1989, 1997, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - The Church and U.S. Foreign Policy Toward Central America, 1985-1986 (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - The Church in Central America, articles, newspaper clippings, 1983-1984, 1990-1991 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Claremont, CA United Church of Christ Congregational Task Force on Central America, minutes, correspondence, programs, 1984-1990 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Claremont, CA United Church of Christ Congregational Task Force on Central America, minutes, correspondence, programs, 1990-1994 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Claremont, CA United Church of Christ Congregational Task Force on Central America and the Carribean, minutes, correspondence, programs, 1994-1996 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Information packets (bibliographies, articles) compiled by James and Margaret Goff for Missionaries, 1970, 1974, 1977, 1985 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Jubilee 2000, booklets and information packet, 1994, 1998, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Liberation Theology, articles, essays incl. Latin American Liberation Theology by Phillip E. Berryman, Protestants in the Latin American Revolution by Emilio Castro, The Role of the Church in Social Change in Latin America by Hiber Conteris, Consumers or Revolutionaries? by Richard Schuall, The Latin American Churches and the Ecumenical Movement by John A. Mackay, 1960-1972 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Liberation Theology, articles, essays incl. Christians for Socialism, Toward a Critical Understanding of Protestant Missions in Latin America by Richard E. Edwards, 1964, 1971-1975 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Liberation Theology, essays incl. Theology of the Liberation of Man by Gustavo Gutierrez, 1988, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous, articles and newspaper clippings, 1988, 1991, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous fund raising letters, 1990-1998 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Peace With Justice Center of Pomona Valley, newsletters, phone lists, programs, 1990-1993 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Preparation Information for 1992 CELAM (Consejo Episcopal Latinoamericano) Conference (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Protestant Church in Central America, articles, essays, news clippings, 1987-1992 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Witness for Peace: Claremont Cluster information, articles, brochures, correspondence, fact sheets, fund raising letters, 1986-1995 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Working papers from 1971 CICOP Conference incl. Man Liberated from Sin and Opperssion: a Theology of Liberation by Alex Morelli (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Food First: News and View newsletter, 1999-2002 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Health Survey and Advice in the Case of Mrs. Coleman C. Hartzler, 1950 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Los Angeles Religion: a Civic Profile by John Orr, 1998 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Les Balfour, Poet and Philosopher, or "a Junkie for Lost Causes," by Leslie Balfour, August 23, 1983 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1992, 1998, 2000 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Publication Catalogs, 1994-1995 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Publication Catalogs, 1996-2000 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Publication Catalogs, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Selected List of Current Books and Pamphlets added to the Missionary Research Library, January-June, 1958 (Box 88, Folder 3)